(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T13:06:21.374820",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
やっとこさ幕開けだ ほら寄ってたかってお手を拝借
At last the curtain rises, come on, gather around and lend a hand!
スタートラインに立った今 そう武装と創と造で登場！！！
Standing on the start line now, armed and creating our entrance!
ここは遊び心で満たそう！
Let's fill this place with playfulness!
あえての戦略なのだ ララララ〜
It's a daring strategy, la la la...
一人でも多くのマヌケが居るなら正すことから始めましょう
If there are fools about, let's start by setting things right.
幸せな時間をどれだけ過ごせるかは
How much happy time we can spend...
微々たるものでも愛に気づけるか さあ試されよう
depends on noticing love in the smallest things. Let's be tested!
パパパッ 晴れた街に
Pa pa pa, in the sunny town,
チャチャチャ 羽ねの心
Cha cha cha, a bounding heart.
ひとりじゃないと否定出来るように 僕は探すんだ
So I can deny that I'm all alone, I'll search for it...
しずけさと一体一 そうか全真剣機をお手を拝借
Silence and one-on-one, with all seriousness, lend a hand!
スタート合図は鳴り止まなく モクノートボントンのはちょうと
The start signal never stops, note by note, harmony by harmony.
ここはトキメキで征くサノバ
This is moving with excitement!
アゲナを付けるなら何が原？
If we're adding excitement, what's the origin?
ひとりでも多くナデガタがなくナデガタブームでいいでしょ
Even if alone, sloping shoulders without a boom is fine, right?
忘れたくないな 偶に不幸に怯えさせるから
I don't want to forget, since sometimes fear of misfortune strikes.
ならスタートに戻ろう パパパッ 晴れた街に
If so, let's return to the start! Pa pa pa, in the sunny town,
チャチャチャ 羽ねの心 ひとりじゃないと否定出来るように
Cha cha cha, a bounding heart. So I can deny that I'm alone,
そしてくれるあなたを 僕は探すんだ
and who solves it for you—I will search for you.
ああ優雅にウィークエンド 耳にタコができるほど聞いた
Ah, gracefully on the weekend, hearing it till our ears are numb,
I(アイ)W(ダブリュー)U(ユー)の言葉だってどこから信じればいいの
even the words of I-W-U, from where should we believe them?
箱に荷物を詰めただけ 気持ちが軽くなったようだ
Just packing luggage into a box, my feelings seem lighter.
悲しみもしまうべきところにしまうべきだ
Even sadness should be put away where it belongs.
幸せと歩め貴重な時間をどれだけ過ごせるかは
Walking with happiness, how much precious time we can spend...
いつでもスタートでよう パパパッ 晴れた街に
let's always be at the start! Pa pa pa, in the sunny town,
パパパッ 晴れた笑顔 ひとりじゃないと…
Pa pa pa, a sunny smile, so I'm not alone...
ハーイ！みんなこんぬいえー！
Hi! Hello everyone!
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！どうもー！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen! Hello!
この度は私の2周年ライブに…
Thank you so very much for coming...
2周年記念ライブにお越しいただきまして、誠に誠にありがとうございます！
to my 2nd anniversary live today!
みんな元気ー？
Is everyone doing well?
おお見てる見てるね！ありがとうね！ありがとうね！
Oh, I see you! Thank you so much!
1階席？あ、2階席？あり、ありな…あ、1階席だ (笑) よろしくね！
First-floor seats? Ah, second? Wait, ah, first-floor! (Laughs) Nice to meet you!
今日はね、たくさんたくさん歌っていきます。
Today I'll be singing lots and lots of songs.
あの、なんか結構ね、あのシャトリツメメツメになってしまったので…
Umm, since the setlist got super packed and tight...
割とあの、淡々とトークしていきますよ(笑) ということでですね、
I'll be talking rather calmly! (Laughs) So...
ここから先たくさんあの、歌っていきますので、ぜひぜひ楽しんでください！
from here on out I'll be singing a bunch more, so please enjoy!
え、ハッシュタグこちら、ちょっと…これ、不知火フレア2周年記念ライブ、
Um, the hashtag is right here... for the Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Live,
よかったらいっぱいツイートしてくれたら嬉しいです！目指せトレンド1位！
if you could tweet a lot I'd be so happy! Let's aim for #1 trending!
よろしくお願いしまーす！ということで、セカンドアニバーサリーライブ、
Thank you so much! So, for our Second Anniversary Live,
「みんなで盛り上がろう」というサブタイトルを、つぶやきつつ、大声で叫びつつ、
with the subtitle "Let's Get Hype Together", tweeting and shouting out loud,
次の曲を歌っていくんですけど、次は、あの、もう1曲私のその曲を聞いてもらったあと、
I'll be singing the next song. After you listen to another one of my songs,
えっと、続けてコラボかな？続けて、あのコラボパートに映っていきますのでね、
we'll be moving on to... is it a collab? Moving on to the collab part,
あの、楽しんでくださいね！(笑) はーい！
so please look forward to it! (Laughs) Yay!
ということで、皆さん、いいですか？
So everyone, are you ready?
あの、あれですよ、次の曲は、やっぱり私のね、お約束ということで、いきなりきちゃいますよ！
Umm, as promised, the next song is coming right up!
いきますよ！それでは聞いてください、スマイルアンードゴー！
Here we go! So please listen to "Smile and Go!!"
こんぬい！準備はいいか？今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！せーの！はい！はい！
Konnui! Are you ready? Let's make some noise together today! Ready, set, go! Hey! Hey!
やってきたんだ みんなに会える時間です
The time has finally come when I can meet everyone!
ふたとかげえむとか 見て欲しくて 泣いちゃうかもね
Watching Futatokage and games, I might even cry because I wanted you to see it so bad!
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に 乗り遅れないよう 手をつなごう
Days slip by in a flash, so let's hold hands so we don't fall behind!
もうちょっとだけ一緒に行こう
Let's stay together just a little longer!
気づけば隣にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for always being right by my side before I even noticed!
そんな高い壁だって ひとっ飛びで飛び越えて 誰も見たことない世界に みんなで行こうよ
Let's all go together to a world no one has ever seen before, leaping over high walls in a single bound!
キミとSmile and Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
You and Smile and Go!! Those who enjoy win the game!
はじけたもん勝ち ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ？
Those who let loose win! If we gather here with smiles, isn't that the best?
ボクらSmile and Go!! いつも全力で
Our Smile and Go!! Always giving it our all,
遊び枕をたて この日常が大切な宝物だよ My and Go!!
resting our play pillows, this everyday life is a precious treasure, My and Go!!
雑談配信 今日はまったり行こうよ
Today's chatting stream, let's take it easy and relax!
他愛ない話聞いてほしくて ちょっと聞いてよ
I want you to listen to my silly stories, so please listen!
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど
I thought about taking a break every once in a while,
やっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな
but I guess I'll just do a late-night drinking stream after all!
巡り会えたこのときも 一緒に過ごしたら
If we spend this time we met together,
いつの間にかキラキラと 太陽よりも輝いて 言葉にはできない思いが あふれ出してしまうよ
before I knew it, shining brighter than the sun, overflowing with feelings too big for words!
君とレッツ・エンジョイって当ててみようよ
Let's try guessing "Let's enjoy with you!"
君とレッツ・エンジョイ！ 心は一つに
Let's enjoy with you! Our hearts as one,
どこにいたって優しさは
wherever we are, kindness
届いてるよ！
reaches you!
僕らレッツ・エンジョイ！ テンション上げてさ
Let's enjoy, everyone! Raising our tension,
僕らレッツ・エンジョイ！ はしゃぎまくらはきっと
Let's enjoy, everyone! Playing around will surely
明日はもっと楽しいこと
bring even more fun
待っているから！
waiting for us tomorrow!
2周年 みんな 本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much for our 2nd anniversary!
まだまだ この先も みんなとたくさん盛り上がりたいから！
We want to get even more hyped up with everyone from now on too!
最後までちゃんとついてきてね！
Make sure to follow us all the way to the end!
飛び起き！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Jump up! One, two, three, four!
芸能！一緒に！
Entertainment! Together!
レッツ・エンジョイ・ワン・ゴー！
Let's Enjoy & Go!!
ずっと見ていて 私のことを
Keep watching me all the time,
これからもずっと 期待してね
and keep expecting great things from me from now on too.
予測不可能な ワクワクを君に
Delivering unpredictable excitement to you,
送るから！
we'll send it your way!
君とスマイル＆ゴー 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go, whoever enjoys it most wins!
君とスマイル＆ゴー はじけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go, whoever bursts with energy wins!
ここに笑顔で 集まれば最高でしょ？
If we gather here with smiles, isn't that the best?
僕らスマイル＆ゴー いつも全力で
Us, Smile & Go, always giving it our all,
僕らスマイル＆ゴー 遊びまくろうだって
Us, Smile & Go, let's play to our heart's content,
この日常が 大切な宝物だよ
because this everyday life is a precious treasure.
飛び切りの笑顔でいこう！
Let's go with our absolute best smiles!
スマイル＆ゴー！
Smile & Go!
はぁ、なんかベース弾けると寂しいな。誰か一緒に弾いてくんないかなー！
Ah, playing bass by myself is kind of lonely. I wonder if someone will play with me!
パートナー！おっ、ふりゃー！
Partner! Oh, Fu-rya!
ベース
Bass...
いや、ギター弾けないけどさ！
No, I can't play guitar, though!
きちゃったぜ！
But I came anyway!
名前から間違えてんだよ！
You got the name wrong right from the start!
え、弾けないけど持ってきてくれたの？
Eh, you brought it even though you can't play?
そうだよ、なんかパートナーがどうしてもの言うからね。
Yeah, because my partner kept insisting on it.
ちょっと持ってくるだけ持ってきてみた。
So I just brought it along.
じゃあ、周年祝しよ！
Well then, let's celebrate the anniversary!
デビューに祝しよ！
Let's celebrate our debuts!
おめでとう！ パートナーもおめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations to my partner too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
パートナーもデビューねって、なんだよ！
"Congratulations on your debut too" - what is that?!
パートナーもデビューね、あれ3周年？
Congratulations on your debut too... wait, 3rd anniversary?
あ、そうなんです
Ah, is that so?
もうね、おめでとうございます！
Well, congratulations!
ありがとうございまーす！いやいや本当に おめでとうだよね。
Thank you very much! Seriously, huge congratulations.
お互いね、おめでとうっていう。本当本当本当！
Congratulations to each other. Really, really, really!
全然関係ない曲をちょっとパトラに弾いていただいたので
Since we had Patra play a song that has completely nothing to do with it,
一緒に歌いたいなと
I wanted us to sing it together.
いや関係なくないよ、あの歌はもう我々というかまぁフレアをね、表した
No, it's not unrelated! That song represents us—or rather, Fu-rya!
ものすごいぴったりな...どういう意味だよ、意味分かんないからさ、今！
It fits so well... What does that mean?! I don't get what you mean right now!
今回歌う曲はパトラが弾いてくれるので、パトラはガチで弾いてます。
The song we're singing this time, Patra is playing, so Patra is playing for real.
あ、はい、弾きました！
Ah, yes, I played it!
で私のほうは、エアギターとなって...でもなんか決まってんだよね！
And as for me, it became an air guitar... but you've got it all set, right!
えー！ほら超かっこいいんだけど！
Eeh! Look, it's super cool!
はい、ということでぜひぜひ聞いてください！
Right, with that said, please definitely give it a listen!
はいよ！はい！かわいい！
Alright, yes! So cute!
今日も駅の改札前で やけにイチャイチャしてるカップル見てへこむ
Feeling down seeing couples getting all lovey-dovey in front of the station ticket gates today too.
知りてえなリア充の生態 見てえなリア充の 憧れの傷跡ちょうだい羨ましい
I wanna know how popular people live, I wanna see their scars of yearning, I'm so jealous.
30超えたらもって始めるとか 先輩の言葉だけ信じて
Believing only my senior's advice to start after turning 30,
予定日人生特訓してそうやわ これじゃまずいよ何とかせんとさ
training hard for the big day, if this keeps up we're in trouble, gotta do something.
偶然拾い捨てられたりと 過ごしていたら運命の出会いさ
If we spend our days picking up discarded things, we'll have a fateful encounter.
あんたに出会った日には ちゃんと気持ち伝えへんといけへんな
On the day I met you, I've gotta properly convey my feelings.
君はかわいいこうしてかわいいやんけ
You're cute, being so cute like that,
魅力があふれてこぼれるやんけ 恥ずかしい声で恥ずかしやんけ
charm overflowing everywhere, embarrassing voice, embarrassing isn't it,
気持ちええ声で気持ちええやんけ
feeling good with a great voice, feeling awesome.
君はかわいいこうしてかわいいやんけ 魅力があふれてこぼれるやんけ
You're cute, being so cute like that, charm overflowing everywhere,
楽しい声で楽しやんけ 嬉しい声でうれしやん香川だな
having fun with a happy voice, overjoyed with a glad voice!
今日も駅のエレベーターで アデヤケニイチャイチャしてるカップル見て
Today too, seeing couples getting lovey-dovey in the station elevator...
さあさあ始まりました高校生活
Now then, high school life has begun!
はたしてハッピーエンドで終わるのでしょうか
Will it end with a happy ending, I wonder?
もしも彼氏なんてできちゃったり!?
What if I somehow get a boyfriend?!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Time to fully enjoy the JK life!
パーティー！
Party!
もう全然ダメダメだテスト勉強
I'm doing so terribly on test prep.
数学なんて使わないじゃん微分積分
Who even uses math like calculus anyway?
何とかなるっしょ！必死一夜漬けでね
It'll somehow work out with last-minute cramming!
笑顔で乗り切れ3人娘
Get through it with a smile, trio girls!
ハレバレ！
Bright and clear!
ご褒美はスイーツ
Our reward is sweets!
ライブも行きたいな
We wanna go to a live show too.
お泊り会して恋バナ
Having a sleepover and talking about love
秘密なしだからね！
Because we have no secrets!
foo！
Foo!
ヒロインJK目指せ
Aiming to be heroine high school girls,
モジモジしてらんない
We can't afford to be shy.
モブなんじゃいられない
We refuse to stay as mere extras!
好きなことで進め
Move forward with what you love,
後悔なんてしない
And have no regrets.
我慢なんて勿体ない
Holding back is such a waste.
期待のJKなのです
We are the hopeful high school girls!
ハラハラしてください
Please keep on the edge of your seat.
優等生じゃいられない
We can't just be honor students!
言いたいことは言って
Say what you want to say,
やりたいことはやって
Do what you want to do.
我慢なんてしてらんない
We won't hold ourselves back anymore!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Fully enjoy the JK life,
パーティー！
Party!
テストも終わった打ち上げだー！
The tests are over, time to celebrate!
カラオケ行こー！
Let's go to karaoke!
いいね！金銭はお互いの手たのもー！
Sounds good! Let's pool our money!
「OK！」推し曲ロメオデュエット
"OK!" Let's duet our favorite song Romeo.
「さあおいデ」
"Come here."
「ちょっ、ちょっ！」
"Wait, wait!"
放課後全力3人娘
After-school energetic trio girls,
ハレバレ！
Bright and clear!
のろけ話聞いて
Listen to our love stories,
バイト愚痴も聞いて
Listen to our part-time job gripes too.
お泊り会して夜更かし
Having a sleepover and staying up late,
カロリー解放日！yeah！
Calorie liberation day! Yeah!
ヒロインJKなって
Becoming a heroine high school girl,
モテ期で悩みタイ
Wanting to worry about being popular.
かもす犬じゃいられない
We can't stay shy.
ネガティブなんてボイで
Throw away negativity,
ポジティブ抱きしめて
Embrace positivity.
青春するの照れないで
Don't be shy to live youth to the fullest.
ルーキーJKなのです
We are rookie high school girls!
ドキドキしてください
Please make your heart skip a beat.
センパイ達にも負けない
We won't lose to the seniors either!
苦手もちょっと挑戦
Take on a bit of a challenge with weaknesses.
大好きもっと磨け
Polish what you love even more.
芋女って言わせない！
Won't let anyone call us country girls!
ファイティング！
Fighting!
友達だよね
We're friends, right?
当たり前っしょ
Obviously!
お泊り会してパーティー！
Having a sleepover party!
秘密なしだからね！
Because we have no secrets!
foo！
Foo!
ヒロインJK目指せ
Aiming to be heroine high school girls,
モジモジしてらんない
We can't afford to be shy.
モブなんじゃいられない
We refuse to stay as mere extras!
好きなことで進め
Move forward with what you love,
後悔なんてしない
And have no regrets.
我慢なんて勿体ない
Holding back is such a waste.
期待のJKなのです
We are the hopeful high school girls!
ハラハラしてください
Please keep on the edge of your seat.
優等生じゃいられない
We can't just be honor students!
言いたいことは言って
Say what you want to say,
やりたいことはやって
Do what you want to do.
我慢なんてしてらんない
We won't hold ourselves back anymore!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Fully enjoy the JK life,
パーティー！
Party!
ギターまじやんけ！
That guitar is for real!
本当、緊張になりそう
Seriously, I'm getting so nervous!
緊張になっちゃうじゃん
You're gonna make me nervous too!
いや、ぽ、ポルポラさんのベース上手ですね
Um, Polpora-san, your bass playing is so good!
ベースはあの、お腹の上ね、こう、ももも、寄せながらやってた
The bass is, you know, right on my tummy!
ガチじゃん！
For real!
ガチ、ガチ、ガチ、ガチ！
For real, for real!
いや、でも今日はね、本当にありがとうございました。
Yeah, but seriously, thank you so much today!
記念グッズ出そうよ、せっかく！
Let's release anniversary goods!
ね、あの、持ってるからね！
Right, because we have them!
よーし、どう？こういう
Alright, how's this?
あれ、なんか、身長差ちょっとおかしくない？
Huh, isn't the height difference a bit weird?
私測ったら2センチしか違わないんだけど
When I measured, there's only a 2cm difference!
そうなんだっけ？
Is that so?
こう、こう？
Like this, like this?
ちょっと私のこれが見えないね
Wait, I can't see this one.
ちょっと下がったほうが… こう、こう、こう
Lower yourself a bit... Like this, like this.
あ、いいね、いいね、いいね
Ah, nice, nice, nice!
いっぱい撮って、いっぱい撮って！
Take lots of pictures!
はい！
Yes!
これ結構難しかったね
That was pretty difficult, huh?
難しかったねえ！
It really was!
そして、え、ポルポラさん何か今日はあの、話しておきたいことがあるとか
And, Polpora-san, is there anything you wanted to say?
あ、そうなんですよ
Ah, that's right.
8月10日はそう、ポルポラ誕生日でございます！
August 10th is Polpora's birthday!
そりゃそうだよね、こんなね
Of course, right?
何の予定もないのに来てくれるわけがない！
There's no way you'd come without any plans!
そんなことない！
That's not true!
今日は強制しに来たんだよ！お誕生日！
I came to celebrate your birthday!
ありがとうございます、そしてお誕生日
Thank you, and happy birthday!
あとはね、あのね、ノーフレ花なんだけど…
And also, about NoeFlare...
まい！ないちゃん！
Marine! Noel-chan!
まりちゃん！
Marine-chan!
んー？
Hmm?
のえちゃん？
Noel-chan?
なんか、つまんねえや
Somehow, this is boring.
あれ？
Huh?
なんかさ、まりもつまんねえなって思ってたんだけどさ
You know, I was thinking it's kind of boring too.
フレアいないとつまんないね
Without Flare, it's boring.
のが詰まんないんだけど
It's getting boring, you know.
なに？お前、なんだよ
What? Hey, what is it?
なんだよ、んー？
What's wrong, hmm?
ちょっと、フレア、早く来い！
Flare, come over here quickly!
来いよ！
Come on!
歌ってるけど…まだまだフレアまだだよー！
We're singing, but... Flare isn't here yet!
おかしいな、おかしいな
That's strange, that's strange.
こんなはずじゃなかったんだけどな
This isn't how it was supposed to go.
てへぺろやん
Oopsie-daisy!
はい！というわけでね
Alright! So anyway,
どうも、二人とも一着目！一着目ね！ありがとうございます！
thank you both for our first outfits! Our first outfits! Thank you!
一着目ということで、ありがとうございます！
Yes, for our first outfits, thank you very much!
ここはどこですか？
Where are we right now?
なんか見たことあるね
It looks kind of familiar.
あるな、ここ。団長ここ知ってるよ。
It does. The Chanchou knows this place.
どこですか？
Where is it?
ここ、あの、海！
Right here, um, the ocean!
そうだけどね！そうだけどね！ここ知ってるよ。
Well, yeah, true! But I know this place.
団長ここで歌ったことあるよ。
The Chanchou has sung here before.
そうだね。そうなんだよ。
That's right. Indeed.
ここはノエルちゃんがね、100万人記念の時に歌ったり、あとSSVとかね。
Noel-chan sang here for her 1 million subscriber milestone, and also for SSV...
そうそうそう！ビーチ！そこのビーチでさ
That's right, right! The beach! On that beach,
3人で歌いたいなってずっと思ってた曲があったの。
there was a song the three of us always wanted to sing together.
なので今日は歌おうかなと思って、ちょっと高いけど大丈夫かな、二人？
So we thought we'd sing it today. It's a bit high-pitched, though—will you two be okay?
大丈夫です！
We'll be fine!
団長も大丈夫です！
The Chanchou will be fine too!
ノエルちゃんは音程の方が心配だね。
Noel-chan, I'm more worried about your pitch.
まあ、そうかね、もうそれはどうしよう。
Well, that's true, nothing we can do about that!
あ、ぽぽぽぽ、足ぽぽぽ、早口だな。
Ah, popopopo, foot popopo, you're talking fast.
じゃあ早速だけど、ちょっと歌おうよ。
Well then, let's get right into it and sing!
真夏の日に一曲聞いてください、「adrenaline!!!」
Please listen to this song on a midsummer day, "adrenaline!!!"
単純な言葉 重ねていく
Simple words are piled up,
もっと心は素直で
making the heart more honest.
なんでもないような その笑顔が
A smile that looks like nothing at all
明日を照らす光に
becomes the light that illuminates tomorrow.
ずっと気づいてたんだって
You said you had noticed it all along,
この手に抱えてたんだって
you said you had been holding it in your hands.
弾けた声に流した答えが
The answer poured out into a bursting voice
今そっときっと願いこめた
is now gently, surely imbued with a wish.
ずっと まわるまわる 夢の中で 繰り返し君と踊った
Always, spinning and spinning in a dream, I danced with you over and over again.
揺れる景色 道は続く
Swaying scenery, the road continues,
通り過ぎる風にふかれて 何度も
blown by the passing wind, time and time again.
越えて行けるから 境界線 雲かき分け手を伸ばした
Because we can cross over the boundary line, I pushed aside the clouds and reached out my hand.
涙は今 浮かぶ空に 預けて 走り出すの
Entrusting my tears to the sky floating right now, I start to run.
並んで見つけた 輝く光を手にと
Holding the shining light we found side by side in our hands.
問題はいつも自分次第 さあ未来を選んで
The problem is always up to yourself, come, choose the future.
こんがらがった糸ほぐしたら 思いのまま進もう
If you untangle the tangled thread, let's go forward just as you feel.
毎日冒険なんだって 奇跡は無限大なんだって
Every adventure is everyday, miracles are infinite.
高鳴る想い 羅針盤のように 今そっときっと導いて
Like a compass for my throbbing feelings, now gently, surely guiding me.
そうだ！めぐるめぐる 波に乗っかっていって 風まかせ君と笑った
That's right! Riding on the spinning, spinning waves, leaving it to the wind, I laughed with you.
予想外は想定内 間違いや失敗も楽しんで
The unexpected is within expectations, enjoying mistakes and failures too.
一歩 踏み出したら 見えた可能性 行き止まりの壁壊して
Possibilities seen once I took a step forward, breaking down the wall of a dead end.
まだ知らない世界 君と一緒なら 怖くないよ
If I'm with you in a world I don't know yet, I'm not scared.
わくわくしている 今が一番大好き
The present moment, when I'm so excited, is my absolute favorite.
ゆっくり 焦らない 自分の歩幅で行こう
Slowly, don't rush, let's go at our own pace.
大丈夫 心配ない 描いたもの全部叶えるよ
It's alright, don't worry, all the things we drew will come true.
ずっと まわるまわる 夢の中で 繰り返し君と踊った
Always, spinning and spinning in a dream, I danced with you over and over again.
いつか君と約束した 願いの架け橋を渡って
Crossing the bridge of wishes I promised you someday.
何度も 越えて行けるから 境界線 雲かき分け手を伸ばした
Because we can cross over the boundary line time and time again, I pushed aside the clouds and reached out my hand.
涙は今 浮かぶ空に 預けて 走り出すの
Entrusting my tears to the sky floating right now, I start to run.
並んで見つけた 輝く光を手にと
Holding the shining light we found side by side in our hands.
わくわくしている 今が一番大好き
The present moment, when I'm so excited, is my absolute favorite.
ゆっくり 焦らないで
Take it slow, don't rush,
自分の歩幅で行こう 大丈夫 心配ない
let's go at our own pace.
ずっと まわるまわる夢の中で 繰り返し君と踊った
Spinning on and on in a dream,
dancing with you over and over.
いつか君と約束した 願いの架け橋を渡って
Crossing the bridge of wishes I promised you someday.
何度も 超えて行けるから 境界線 雲かき分け 手を伸ばした
Because we can cross over and over,
parting clouds at the border.
涙は 今 浮かぶ空に 預けて走り出すの
Entrusting my tears to the floating sky, I start running.
並んで 見つけた 輝く光を 手に
Holding the shining light we found side by side.
問題は いつも自分次第 さぁ未来を選んで
The problem is always up to us,
now choose the future.
こんがらがった糸ほどいたら 思いのまま進もう
Untangling the twisted threads,
let's move forward as we wish.
毎日 冒険なんだって 奇跡は 無限大なんだって
Every day is an adventure,
miracles are infinite.
高鳴る 想い 羅針盤のように 今 そっと きっと 導いてく
A throbbing feeling like a compass,
guiding us softly and surely.
そうだよ！めぐるめぐる波に乗っかって 風まかせ君と笑った
Riding the spinning waves, I laughed with you at the wind's mercy.
ゆっくり 焦らないで 自分の歩幅で行こう
Take it slow, don't rush,
let's go at our own pace.
大丈夫 心配ない 描いたもの 全部叶えるよ
It's alright, no worries,
all our dreams will come true.
ずっと まわるまわる夢の中で 繰り返し君と踊った
Spinning on and on in a dream,
dancing with you over and over.
いつか君と約束した 願いの架け橋を渡って
Crossing the bridge of wishes
I promised you someday.
はぁ〜疲れた〜
Phew, I'm tired~
やばたーん
Yabatan!
疲れちゃった
So tired.
ありがとー
Thank you~
このさ、水冷たいよね
The water here is so cold, right?
足元冷たいよ
Our feet are freezing.
水に入ってさ
Let's go into the water.
グラビア写真撮らない？
Should we take gravure photos?
あ、いいね！
Oh, sounds good!
こういう感じ？
Like this?
こういう感じに決まってるでしょ
It's obviously supposed to look like this.
ここ風呂じゃねえんだよ
This isn't a bath, you know.
みんなでやれば風呂じゃない、みんなやって
If we all do it, it's not a bath! Everyone do it.
あ、集まれ！団長も一緒と
Ah, gather around! Dancho too.
え、まりん、おっぱい大きいの禁止ね
Marine, big boobs are prohibited!
え、無理だよみんな
Eh, that's impossible for everyone.
お前さ！
Hey you!
おい、乳首隠して
Hey, cover your nipples.
どう、どうすればいいの？
What, what should we do?
色気、色気、色気
Seductive, seductive, seductive.
ねぇなんか顔もでかそう、もう少し前行って
Hey, your face looks big, move a bit forward.
顔のでかさがこのくらいかな
Is the head size about this much?
おい隠してんだよ！かまってんだよ！
Hey, I'm hiding it! You're paying attention to me!
もうやだ！
No way!
やだやだやだ
No no no.
こんな恋なんて
Such a romance...
ねえ、全然セクシーじゃないよ、マリン
Hey, it's not sexy at all, Marine.
ちゃんとセクシー見ないよ
You gotta look properly sexy.
これがみたかったやつ？
Is this what you wanted to see?
なんかひとりだけ子供が混じってる
It looks like there's a child mixed in.
今たぶんさ、スクショされてる
Right now you're probably being screenshot.
のしるってないからねそれ
That's not how you do noshiru.
もうちょっと上から行けますか？
Can we go a bit from above?
で、ちょい引き行けます、これ
Can we pull back a little, like this?
で、ちょっとだけ下のほうがいいかな？
And maybe slightly lower is better?
お、こういう感じ？
Oh, like this?
セクシー！
Sexy!
いいじゃん、いいじゃんお姉さん組
Not bad, the older sisters team!
暑いね
It's hot.
眩しい太陽をちょっと誰か加工しといてください
Someone please edit out the dazzling sun.
眩しい感じにしといてね
Make it look dazzling.
あとは？やりたいことある？
What else? Anything you want to do?
今のうちにやりたかったことだよ
Things we wanted to do while we can.
ほんと？どうしようか
Really? What should we do?
立ち上がって、うみこ、海のポーズ
Stand up, Umiko, ocean pose.
えー、サメのポーズ
Eww, shark pose.
誰が見たいのそれ！
Who wants to see that?!
え、団員さんは見たいはず、フレアさんは見たいって
Danin-san wants to see, Flare said she wants to see.
じゃ、このおっぱいをアップにしてもらって
Then have these boobs zoomed in.
食べ取られた！
Eaten up!
食べ取られたの！
She ate it!
美しい姫が出ちゃった
A beautiful princess appeared.
美しかったね。事件性はないけども
It was beautiful. Though there's no foul play.
ありがとね、サシンもね
Thanks for the photos too.
照らしてもらって
Getting illuminated.
終わりだよね、ずっといよう
It's over, let's stay here forever.
もう終わりよ！
It's over!
帰った帰ったちけーあらい、ありがとありがと
Go home, go home, get away, thanks thanks.
はい、ありがとー
Yup, thanks~
あれ？なんだか呼ばれているような気がする
Huh? I feel like I'm being called.
誰だろう、この声は、ちょっと行ってきます！
Who could it be... I'll go check it out!
あらためて、フレアは私の
Once again, Flare is my...
おー！
Whoa!
いや！
Hey!
鳴らしてみなさいよ！
Go on, try playing it!
鳴らすよー！
I will!
くらい、ぼー！
Dark, bo—!
あれ？肝心のフレアが二人わ？
Wait, where are the two other Flares?
こないなんですけど！
They're not showing up!
今日カーニバルって聞いたんですけど！
I heard today was supposed to be a carnival!
おーたー！
Ooh!
フレア！
Flare!
どこにいたのー！
Where were you?!
あー！
Ah!
なんか来た！
Something came!
入るタイミング逃したかなって思った！
I thought I missed my cue to enter!
何持ってんの！
What are you holding?!
なんすかそれは！
What is that?!
これは、アコーディオンだ！
This is an accordion!
おー！かっこいい！
Ooh! So cool!
わためは何持ってんの？
What do you have, Watame?
おー、大太鼓だー！
Ooh, a bass drum!
おー、でか！でか！でか！
Whoa, huge! Huge! Huge!
フレアのは？これなんかチューバ？
What about Flare's? Is this like a tuba?
チューバ？
A tuba?
チューバかな？
Is it a tuba?
なかなかだな、ぶー、だ、強そう。
Pretty nice, boo, looks strong.
それめっちゃ攻撃力高そう。
That looks like it has super high attack power.
今日は、みんなでね、楽器をマッチングしながら！
Today, we're matching instruments together
いたいーだい曲があるんだよね！
and playing a big song, you know!
なになになになに？なにを歌うか？
What, what, what? What are we singing?
この景色見て！ちょっと綺麗じゃない？
Look at this scenery! Isn't it kind of pretty?
えー！
Eh!
美しい。
Beautiful.
ちょっと脇潰ししっかりしなきゃね。
We gotta make sure our flanks are covered.
やめなさい、やめなさい。
Cut it out, cut it out.
でもある程度敵わきそうだから、おくとかヤバイから、ちょっとやばいね。
Mobs might spawn, so placing things there is dangerous.
ガチらみないで。
Don't look at it too seriously.
だから、ちょっとみんなで歌おう！
So let's all sing together!
タイトルコール！
Title call!
はい！
Ready!
炎と森のカーニバル！
Flame and Forest Carnival!
横浜にある
In Yokohama,
遊園地のコスモパニックの非常口が
the emergency exit of an amusement park called Cosmo Panic
このパーティーのエントランス
is the entrance to this party.
扉を開けたらそこは巨大な樹が
When you open the door, a giant tree
支配する、会場の名は
presides over the venue called
"ツリーランド"
"Tree Land."
君はここでは大スター
You're a big star here.
ほら、鐘がなった パーティーが始まる
Look, the bell rings, the party begins.
炎と 森の カーニバル
The carnival of flame and forest,
ミイラ男も踊っている
even the mummy is dancing.
今宵、僕が招かれた カーニバル
Tonight, the carnival I was invited to.
魔法使いは僕に言ったんだ
The magician told me,
「この恋は秘密にしておくんだよ
"You must keep this love a secret,
さもなければこの子の命が危ない」と。
otherwise this girl's life is in danger."
「私をパーティーへ連れ出して」
"Take me out to the party,"
君がそうやって言うからさ
you said to me so urgently,
悪魔のdjを観に行こうか
shall we go see the demon DJ?
月のカクテルを買ってくるよ
I'll go buy us a moon cocktail.
barのロボットに見惚れていたら
When I got mesmerized by the robot at the bar,
君がそうやって怒るからさ
you got all angry about it,
人目を気にしないでキスをした
so I kissed you without caring who was watching.
ほら、君の出番だろう?
See, isn't it your turn now?
炎と 森の カーニバル
The carnival of flame and forest,
シンデレラも歌っている
even Cinderella is singing.
今宵、僕が招かれた カーニバル
Tonight, the carnival I was invited to.
人ごみの中、離れないように
So we wouldn't get separated in the crowd,
君と手を繋いだんだ、この君の手を
I held your hand, deciding never
もう離さないと 僕は決めたんだ
to let go of your hand ever again.
この森のカーニバル
This forest carnival,
ミイラ男も踊ってる
Even a mummy is dancing,
今宵 僕が招かれたカーニバル
In this carnival I was invited to tonight.
魔法使いは 僕に言ったんだ
The magician told me,
この恋は秘密にしておくんだよ
"You must keep this love a secret,
さもなければ この子の命が
otherwise this girl's life..."
危ないよ
is in danger.
はーい！どうだった？ 楽器。
Yay! How were the instruments?
いやこれ持って！
Hey, hold this!
片方これそうだね？
This one's pretty tough, right?
片方ちゃうよこれ！
That's not the half of it!
いや強かったよ！
Man, it was intense!
いや、めっちゃ強かったよもう！
Yeah, it was super intense!
いやー、肺活量もっとる。
Man, it takes so much lung capacity.
いや頑張った、頑張った！
Man, we did our best!
腕がね…
My arms...
腕が！腕が！
My arms! My arms!
大変だったね。みんな疲れたね。
That was tough. Everyone's tired, huh?
ネスタイクだってよ。
Ness-taiko, they say.
ナイスだね。ナイスだったよ。
Nice, huh? It was nice.
強そう。ドン！ジャーン！
Looks strong. Boom! Ta-da!
じゃーん！痛っ！
Ta-da! Ouch!
フレアそれつけてたの？ちゃんと。
Flare, were you wearing that properly?
ちゃんと。ゆうる、ゆうる、おー、いいね、いいね。
Properly. Loose, loose, oh, nice, nice.
優雅だね。
Graceful, huh?
でもね、引くことに夢中になるこれ。ね？
But you get so absorbed in playing it, right?
ホップはどこへ？あれ？またね？
Where'd Hop go? Huh? Again?
ホップ？なんのことだ？
Hop? What are you talking about?
記憶になかった。
I had no memory of that.
ホップはしてた！
Hop was doing it!
この中に入ってんじゃいかな？
Maybe they went inside here?
あ、その中！あ、なるほどね。
Oh, inside there! Ah, I see.
そういうことしてたよ！可愛いよ！
That's what you were doing! So cute!
しまってあるの！可愛いよ！
It's packed away! So cute!
ということでね、せっかくこうやって楽器持っているので、はい！
So since we've got instruments out like this, yes!
スクショ、しますか？あ、記念撮影！記念撮影！ぜひぜひ！
Shall we take a screenshot? A commemorative photo!
やっぱアップでさ、こうマーチング感出したい。あ、いいね、マーチング感！
I want a close-up to give it that marching band feel.
いいね。こう、いしょ、ど、ど、ど、
Nice. Like this, yo-heave-ho, do, do, do,
こう、こう、こう、いしょ、こう、あ、いい、いい。
like this, like this, like this, yo...
こう、こう、こう、どん、そう！こう！
Like this, like this, like this, boom, right!
イエーイ！向きが、向きが。ちょっと、それ違っちゃうよ！
Yay! The direction, wait, that's wrong!
逆だ逆だ！あっちだ！当たってる！
It's backwards! That way! It's hitting!
こっち？ちょろって出てるほうがいいじゃん。こっち？イエーイ！
This way? It's better if it sticks out a little. Yay!
イエーイ！いい感じ！いい感じ！
Yay! Looking good! Looking good!
こう、どう？いぇーい！
Like this, how is it? Yay!
いぇーい！回るな回るな！いぇーい！回るな回るな！イエーイ！
Yay! Don't spin, don't spin! Yay!
イエーイ！良い感じ！
Yay! Looking great!
撮れたかな？撮れた？撮ってくれましたか？
Did we get it? Did you take it for us?
お、良いのでは？いいのでは？ありがとう、二人とも！
Oh, is this good? Thank you, both of you!
いや、楽しかった！楽しかったね！ありがとうございまーす！
Man, that was fun! Thank you so much!
じゃあ、このままおだめ この森で、あ、儀式の続きをしよう。
Well then, just like this in this forest, ah, let's continue the ritual.
儀式の続き？この森とはため
The continuation of the ritual? This forest and Watame...
今宵は人気スカーン！
Tonight is a popular scarn!
さもなければ この子の命が ああ、危ないよ！おかしいだろ！
Otherwise this girl's life... Ah, it's dangerous! That's strange!
ということで、色々準備するのでね、フレアはこのまま記念楽しんでくれ！
So, we're going to prepare various things, so Flare, enjoy the memorial!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
分けたら分けてね！
Share it if you get some!
分けるよ！ありがとう！
I'll share! Thank you!
あ、私もうなんか呼ばれてるから、私もう一緒に行くわちょっと。
Ah, I'm being called, so I'll go together for a bit.
あ、本当 に？じゃあ一緒に。
Ah, really? Then let's go together.
じゃあ一緒にじゃあ。したの方へゴー！
Then let's go downwards! Go!
行きたくないな、なんかけんだよ。
I don't really want to go, somehow.
いくんだよ！
You're going!
いやだな。
I don't want to.
行くよ！
Let's go!
こんばんは！
Good evening!
今夜は不知火フレア2周年記念！アニバーサリーライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Shiranui Flare's 2nd Anniversary Live!
ホロライブ2期生大丸ポルカです。
I am Hololive 2nd Gen Omaru Polka.
すごいね！後ろまで見えてるよ、みんな！後ろまで見えてるよ！イエーイ！
Amazing! I can see all the way to the back, everyone! Yay!
というわけでね、今ねフレアが頑張っててまだ走ってる途中だからうん。そろそろ来るかな？サライでも歌っとくかな？
So, Flare is working hard right now, will she be here soon? Should I sing Sarai?
おースタート！じゃあ呼ぶぞ！みんなで行くよ！じゃあ呼ぶからね？
Oh, then let's call her! Everyone, let's go! So I'll call her, okay?
ええ、なんて呼ぼう？フレアでいっか。せーの！フレアー！
Um, what should I call her? Flare is fine. Ready? Flare!
あれ？
Huh?
あの森から来る、来るはずだったんだけどな、なんか。
She was supposed to come from the forest...
森から、え？
From the forest, huh?
もう一回気を取り直して、もっともっと大きい声で！せーの、不知火フレア――！
Let's try that again with a bigger voice! Ready, go! Shiranui Flare!
腰が、どうもありがとうございました！
My back... thank you very much!
え、じゃあ、全然あの私これ見て帰らせていただきます。
Well then, I'll just watch this and head home.
帰るな、帰るな。
Don't go home!
疲れた。
I'm tired.
なんか、つなぎだった、えのすけ？
Was this just a filler segment?
いや、そう、実は今日初めて会うんですよね？初めまして！どうもありがとうございました！お疲れ様でしたー！
Actually, today is the first time we're meeting! Nice to meet you! Thank you!
いやいやいや、そういう風にしちゃダメなんですよ、今日。
No, you can't do it like that today.
あのね、かっこいいことするから、かっこいいこと。
We're gonna do cool things.
あ、そうそう、最初にね、かっこいいことするから、あんまり喋らないでくれって言ったんだ、さっき。
I told you earlier not to talk too much because we're doing cool stuff first.
もうだいぶ喋っちゃったわ、もうだいぶ喋っちゃったわ！
I've already talked way too much!
いや、もうね、かっこいい歌、歌っちゃいますか？
Should we sing a cool song?
あ、じゃあ、かっこいい曲、歌っちゃいますか？女の子二人でかっこいい歌、歌っちゃいますか？
Shall two girls sing a cool song?
歌っちゃいますか？
Shall we?
盛り上がっていけよ！いけよ！おー！
Let's get hyped! Let's go! Oh!
タイトルコールさせてもらいます。
Let me do the title call.
はい。
Yes.
不死鳥のフランメ。
Fushichou no Furamme.
果てなき 強い この想いは
Endless, strong feelings
譲れない
Cannot be yielded,
強い この想いは
These strong feelings
誰にも 負けない
Will lose to no one.
不死なるメロディ
An immortal melody,
輝けTrue heart
Shine, True heart.
この手から零れ落ちた イノチ…紡いだコ・ド・ウ!
A heartbeat spun from the life spilled from this hand!
欠けたムーンライト その光は 残した者にナニを問う!
The waning moonlight asks what of those left behind!
哀しみを束ねて 剣に 刃に ジャスティスの名の下
Bundling sorrow into a sword and blade in the name of justice.
二度と消えることない 魂の種火をさぁ 灯せ
Light the unquenchable seed fire of the soul now!
燃えない 人に 運命などない
No destiny for those who don't burn.
怯まない 過去を 引き千切って 行きなさい
Tear away the past without flinching and go forth.
アツく 羽ばたき合う 響き伝う 奏で伝う 絆ッ!
Passionate wings beating together, resonating, playing bonds!
そう 涙握りしめて 背負った 全部 握りしめて
Gripping back tears and holding onto everything we bore,
いま不死なる夢を羽根に
Now with an immortal dream on our wings,
願う明日を共に飛ばないか? 歌えPhoenix song
Shall we soar together? Sing, Phoenix song.
燃えない 人に 運命などない
No destiny for those who don't burn.
怯まない 過去を 引き千切って 行きなさい
Tear away the past without flinching and go forth.
アツく 交わし合い 傷つけ合う 傷の数
Scars from passionately exchanging and hurting each other.
涙を 握り締め 手を 繋いだ
Gripping tears and holding hands.
響き伝う 奏で伝う 絆
Resonating and playing bonds.
涙を 握り締め 手を 握りしめ
Gripping tears and gripping hands tightly.
眩しなる 夢を 羽根に
With a dazzling dream on our wings,
願う明日を ともに飛ばないか
Shall we soar to tomorrow together?
ねぇ 明日を共に 今日は 泣かないか
Shall we not cry today and look to tomorrow?
歌え フェニックスソング
Sing, Phoenix song.
迷い生きて見上げた空 どことなく似ていて切なくて
The sky I looked up at while living in doubt, bittersweet.
繋いだはずの温もりを噛みしめ 掌に上を向け
Savoring the warmth, turning our palms upward.
震えるくらいなら 決意を構えて
If you're going to tremble, ready your resolve.
怯まないこと ナニも恐れるな
Without flinching, fear nothing.
震えるくらいなら 決意を構えて
If you're going to tremble, ready your resolve.
迷い生きて見上げた空
The sky I looked up at while living in doubt.
ナイトメア ごときで 怯むな
Do not flinch at the likes of nightmares.
断罪の十字架を 終焉の聖水を
The cross of condemnation, the holy water of the end.
踊れ 踊れ 勇気は決して裏切らない
Dance, dance, courage will never betray you.
数多の星となって 続いた道を照らすんだろ
Becoming stars to illuminate the path we followed.
輝くカオス 未来を心一つにして 今描いた夢を羽根に 手を繋ぎ翼にしよう
Shining chaos, turning dreams into wings and holding hands.
輝くカオス 未来を心一つにして
Shining chaos, uniting our hearts for the future.
今描いた夢を羽根に 手を繋ぎ翼にしよう
Turning today's dreamed dream into wings and flying.
輝くカオス 未来を心一つにして
Shining chaos, uniting our hearts for the future.
守りもののために誓える 誇れる 何も怖くはない
Swearing for what we protect, proud, nothing to fear.
見果てぬ先あるような 魂の灯火をさあ灯せ
Light the beacon of the soul that has no end in sight.
たとえば君が何処にいても
Even if you go anywhere,
必ず僕がさ、迎えに行こうよ
I will definitely go meet you,
大人になってもきっとふたりで
No matter how old we grow, surely the two of us
たくさんの思い出をいっぱい作りに出かけよう
Will go out to make lots of memories together.
どれだけ君のそばにだっていて
No matter how close I am to you,
心は果てしなく遠い宇宙にいるようで
My heart seems to be endlessly far away in the universe,
星の数ほどのたった一つ僕らの出会いはきっと偶然じゃない
Out of countless stars, just the one, our meeting wasn't a coincidence.
言葉が愛を叫ぼうとしてる
Words are trying to shout out love,
細胞のすべてが君を求めてんだ
Every cell in my body is seeking you.
愛を歌え声の限り
Sing love to the limit of your voice,
全身全霊身体中総動員で愛よ届けどうか君の心へ
With all your body and soul, may my love reach your heart.
未来がここで始まりを告げるよ
The future announces its beginning right here.
ちょっと今ので全部使い切ったわ
I used up all my energy on that one!
結構冷静なんですね、ポルカ
You're being pretty calm about it, Polka— I mean, Rushia!
もうちょっと限界なんだわ
I'm pretty much at my limit!
あんまり結構冷静に見えってない
You really don't look very calm at all.
あのね、あのね、私、かっこいい曲が苦手なわけよ。
You see... I'm not really good with cool songs.
ああ、はいはいはい。
Ah, right, right, right.
なので、今日、最初で最後のかっこいい曲なわけ。
So today is my first and last cool song.
なんで、なんで？どういう動き、どういう動きの？
Why, why? What kind of movement was that?
いや、すごく楽しかったけど、ちょっとね
Well, it was a lot of fun, but... you know...
すごいね、やっぱり、コスト高かった
It's amazing, as expected, the cost was high—
ああ、誰が誰がさ、あのソロはねんだよ
Ah, wait, whose solo was that anyway?!
全然、なんかね、ポルカのエッジもね
Not at all! And Polka's edge...
こっちかなと思ったこっちなんだよね
I thought it was this way, but it turned out to be that way!
いや、だて外に広がるだろ、普通考えて
Well, it should spread outwards normally, right?
合わさったら、なんか、全然同じ方向だからいいんだよ！
When they match up, it's totally in the same direction, so it's fine!
もう歌ってる時そんな記憶ないもん、これとか
When I'm singing, I have no memory of things like this!
必死に、ああ、やばい、ああ、いけるいけるみたいな
Desperately thinking, "Ah, crap, ah, I can do this!"
いやでも、かっこよかったよ。うん、かっこよかったです。
But you looked cool. Yeah, you looked really cool.
よくハモれるなって思ってました。いや、もうね、忘れちゃう
I was wondering how you could harmonize so well. Well, you forget!
え、なんかさ、ぶつかる時すごい難しくない？
Eh, like, when bumping into each other, isn't it super hard?
本当にね、必死だよ。
Honestly, we're desperate!
いや、この曲をね、やりたかったのよ、ポルカだとね。
But I really wanted to do this song with Polka.
え、これはね、かっこいい。あ、あのね
Eh, this is... cool. Ah, you know...
私はね、あの、こんなになんだろう、知らなかった、イグニッションっていうとこも知らなかった
I didn't know the "Ignition" part—
イグニッションを知らなかったからさ、そのサビのすごい有名だなっていうところは知ってたんだけど
I didn't know "Ignition," so I only knew that the chorus part was super famous.
イグニッションを知らなかったからめっちゃ焦ったわ。
Since I didn't know "Ignition," I panicked so much!
いや、そう。あの、この曲とね、あの、もう1曲ね、ちょっと迷ってたやつがあったのね。
Yeah, right. There was another song I was hesitating between with this one.
夢すよね、そっち。あ、そうそうそうそう。
"Yumesu," right? Ah, yes yes yes yes.
そっちも知ってました。あの、フリュデゥールって
I knew that one too. Like, "Freude"—
あ、言っちゃった、あ、言っちゃった。言っちゃった。
Ah, I said it! Ah, I said it. I said it!
いや、そっちもね、すごい、あ、え？歌う？
Well, that one is also amazing, ah, eh? Sing it?
ああ、そっちも全然聞こえ合ったら
Ah, if we could hear each other—
あ、聞こえ合ったらね。え？聞こえなかったら？
Ah, if we could hear each other. Eh? If we couldn't hear each other?
え、ていうか、なんかいや、あの、フリュ、あの、フランメはさ、逆のパートとか興味ないの？
Eh, I mean, like, Flare, aren't you interested in the reverse parts?
え、ちょっと、え、その、サビのなんかいったい、音どういうことになってるんですか？
Eh, wait, what on earth is happening with the notes in the chorus?
自分のパートに必死でさ、あの、相手のハモリっていってどのてんなのって
I'm desperate with my own part, and wondering what note the other's harmony is at!
じゃあ、ハモリ教えてくれる？いいよ。あ、ほんと？
Then, will you teach me the harmonies? Sure. Oh really?
じゃ、それだったら、まあ、それならええか。
Well, if that's the case, then I guess that's fine.
聞きたいよね、みんな！
Everyone wants to hear it, right?!
そして、あのさ、こう、聞ききたいよね、ポルカのハモリ。
And then, you know, we want to hear Polka's harmony.
それはいいや。なんでだよ！
I'm good. Why?!
世界一ハモリに向いてない人間だよ！そんなことない、そんなことない！
I'm the least suited person in the world for harmonies! That's not true!
あの、まあ、共演初めてだったのに本当ありがとうございました。これからもよろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much even though it was our first time co-starring. Please keep working with us!
なんでだよ、この社内ユニット感よ。
Why are you acting like an internal company unit?!
ツーショットは？あ、ツーショット、みんな撮ってぜ。
A two-shot? Ah, two-shot, everyone take one.
ツーショット、どうやって撮るんだ?これ。ジャンガジャンガジャンガジャンガ…同じ方向？
How do you take a two-shot? Like this? Jang-ga-jang-ga... in the same direction?
なんか同じ方向なんだよね。かっこいいこと？あんまりない、いいじゃんいいじゃん、こう、そう。
It's like, in the same direction. Is that cool? Not really, it's fine, like this, yeah.
これが、弟子と師匠の最初で最後のが、これ、隠してるみたいなスカートの。
This is the first and last of the disciple and master, hiding it like a skirt.
師匠重いから、下から持ち上げる！持ち上げる！
The master is heavy, so I'll lift her from below! Lift her!
よし、じゃあ、あの、こんな感じで、あのポルカはけるんで、記念写真これでいい？じゃ、お疲れ様でした。
Alright, like this, Polka's leaving, is this photo okay? Well, good work.
いや、本当にそれ、演出か？いや、だ、ありがとうございました。
Wait, was that really a direction? Well, thank you very much!
これからも、フリ、あの、ライブいっぱい楽しんでいこう！楽しんでいこう！
From now on, let's enjoy lots of live performances! Let's enjoy them!
ありがとう、お前のポルカでした。やったー！がんばってねー！
Thank you, that was your Polka! Yay! Do your best!
はい、ありがとう、ポルコー！
Yes, thank you, Polka!
黄色い悲鳴が、ちょっと最後に事件性のある悲鳴を出してもらっていい？
Yellow screams... Can you let out a scream with an incident-like vibe?
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はい、ありがとうございましたー！
Yes, thank you very much!
いやー、濃かったなー。最後のポルカのやつちょっと事件性がありすぎるなー。
Man, that was intense. That last thing with Polka had a bit too much incident vibe.
いや、面白かったー！いや、みんなもどうだったー？
Man, that was fun! How was it for everyone too?
いつもね、仲良くしていただいてる方を今回お呼びさせていただきました！
I've invited some people who are always so nice to me this time!
みんな、本当にありがねー！
Thank you all so much, really!
会いに来てくれて、一緒に踊ってくれて、本当にありがねー！
Thank you so much for coming to see me and dancing along with me!
ということでね、ここからはまたソロパートに戻っていきます。
So, from here on, we're going back to the solo parts.
私一人になってしまったけれどもみんなも一緒に盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです。
I'm all by myself now, but I'd be happy if you all get hyped up together with me.
えー、次の曲はですね、えー、合唱から、あの、混声の合唱ベルから、えーエンディングテーマ歌いたいなと思っております。
Um, the next song is... from a chorus version, a mixed chorus version, I'd like to sing the ending theme.
聞いてください、「つよがり」。
Please listen: "Tsuyogari".
つよがり 作詞：福田哲也 作曲：勝誠二
[Song: Tsuyogari / Lyrics: Tetsuya Fukuda / Music: Seiji Katsu]
放課後の校舎
The school building after school,
柔らかな光
soft light filtering through,
長い影ふたつ
two long shadows
寄り添い少し照れてる
snuggling close and blushing a bit.
泣きたいくせに
Even though you want to cry,
平気な顔で
with a nonchalant face,
胸を張る君を頼りにしているよ
I'm relying on you standing tall.
強がりじゃなくて素直な気持ち
Instead of acting tough, show me
見せてほしいよ私だけに
your honest feelings, just to me.
深呼吸して
Take a deep breath,
そう 何と解ける 言えない言葉
those unsaid words melting away...
君が大好き
I love you so much.
忘れないでいて
Don't ever forget,
誰かが聞いたら
even if someone asks,
笑われてもいい
it's okay if they laugh.
輝く君だけの夢
Your own shining dream,
生まれ変わって
even if we are reborn,
聞いても必ず
I will surely hear it,
出会える二人だよ
the two of us destined to meet.
そう信じてる
I believe that.
諦めないって約束だから
Because it's a promise never to give up,
私も少し強がりだね
I'm also acting a bit tough, aren't I?
二人が描くそれぞれの未来に
Toward the futures we each envision,
向かって走っていこう
let's run forward together.
強がりじゃなくて素直な気持ち見せてほしいよ私だけに
Instead of acting tough, show me your honest feelings, just to me.
深呼吸してそう何と溶ける言えない言葉
Take a deep breath, those unsaid words melting away...
君が大好き
I love you so much.
はぁー、ありがとうございました！
Phew, thank you very much!
なんかずっと、あのコラボパートだったから、なんかあのソロになるとちょっとまた一層、緊張、しましたー！
We were doing that collab part for a while, so being solo again makes me even more nervous!
あとね、ちょっと1曲だけあるんですけど、あのその前に、あのやっぱりちょっとね、あの2周年ということで、あの宣伝してもいいですか？
Also, we have one more song left, but before that, since it's our 2nd anniversary, can I do a little announcement?
みんなもちょっと待っててかもしれないなって、あのみんな行っただろうか、ね、ためとけよって言ったよな？
You guys might have been waiting for it, right? I told you guys to save up for it, didn't I?
ということで、グッズ出まーす！ドーン！
So, the merch is out! Boom!
不知火フレア活動2周年記念グッズ～！どどんぱふぱふ～！
Shiranui Flare's 2nd anniversary merch! Tada, fanfare!
なんでね、あの「いや、これは欲しかったけどこっちはいらないな」みたいなね、そういうのもあるかもしれないんですけどね、全部買ってくれたら一番嬉しいんですけどね。
So, you might think "Well, I wanted this but I don't need that," and while buying everything makes me the happiest,
で、ちなみにですね、ボイス単品販売なんですけど、これの一番上の、あの「私から君へ 二周年を迎えて感謝のメッセージ」
And by the way, for the individual voice sales, the top one is "From Me to You: A Thank You Message for Our 2nd Anniversary."
これね、あの私からの、あの、お便り、ボイスメッセージみたいな感じになっております。
This is basically like a letter or a voice message from me.
私のシンプルな、あの気持ちを、あの、エルフレのみんなに、あの、聞いてもらいたいなって思います。ちょっとボイスドラマ形式にな感じのちょっと始まりはあるんですけど、
I want all the Elf-friends to hear my simple feelings. There's a little voice drama style beginning to it,
あの、こちらですね、メガネ、えっと、ビッグメガネ置きスタンドを迎えに置くとちょっと照れな感じになるかもしれないですね。
and if you place the big glasses display stand in front of you, you might feel a bit shy.
あの、ちなみにあの、なんか野乃されたいボイスみたいなの、あの、生きる人が辛くなる、これね、お前らが求めたんだからな？
By the way, about the voices you want to be scolded by—well, you guys asked for this, right?
ちょっとこれに関しては、あの、私側、私は悪くないからな？
So regarding this, I'm—I'm not in the wrong here, okay?
フルセット購入特典、こちら、え、直筆サイン入りポストカード！こちら数量限定になっておりまーす！
Full set purchase bonus: a postcard with a handwritten signature! This is available in limited quantities!
あの、サインもしかしたら変わるかもって言ってたんですけど、あの、今回はですね、あの販売した段階でのこちらのサインになっておりますので、「あ、変わらないやんけ！」みたいな
I said the signature might change, but this time it's the signature from when it went on sale, so "Ah, it didn't change!"
ということでですね、ぜひぜひ、もし欲しいよって思ってくださる方がいたらね、あの購入してください。
So please, if there are people who think they want it, please buy it.
こちらですね、あの前回の生誕祭のときと同じ量、あの、ご用意しております。
We have prepared the same amount as the previous birthday festival.
だから結構な量をご用意させていただいております。で、生誕祭のね、あのサインの書き終わっておりますので、あの、順次皆さんのところに買ってくださった皆さんのところには発送がそろそろ行くのではないかなと思いますので、こちらもよろしくお願いします。
So we've prepared quite a lot, and they should be shipping out to everyone soon, so please look forward to that too.
はい、そしてですね、え、次にいきますよ。このポストカードなんとタペストリーになります！父さんが描いてくれましたー！可愛いでしょう、飾って！
Yes, and next! This postcard turns into a tapestry! Papa drew it for me! Isn't it cute? Display it!
私がタペストリーを出すのは結構珍しいんですよ。
It's quite rare for me to release a tapestry.
こちらアクリルスタンド！これメガネをね、かけられるんですよ。
This acrylic stand! You can put glasses on it.
こちらさくみち先生にですね、おお願いしましたー！見て見て、可愛いでしょう！
I asked Sakumichi-sensei for this! Look, look, isn't it cute?
こちらもぜひぜひね、あの買って、メガネをかけてくれたらメガネをかける私を見れるかもね。
Please buy this too, and if you put glasses on it, you might get to see me wearing glasses.
え、こちらウォールマグ！これは結構あの会社社畜のみんなにはお役立ていただけるのではないでしょうか。おしゃれなデザインをね、ちょっと目指してみました。
Next, the Wall Mug! This will probably be very useful for corporate workers. I aimed for a fashionable design.
ぜひぜひこちらすべて、あの単品でも販売しておりますので、ぜひぜひこちらもお手に取ってくれたら嬉しいです。グッズ以上です！
Everything is also sold individually, so I'd be happy if you pick them up too. That's all for the merch!
でですね、まだまだちょっと告知したいことがあるのでちょっと巻いた感じでいくんですけど、あのライブ、これでお、あと1曲歌ったら終わりなんですけど、もうちょっとね、アンコール！アンコール！って
And I still have more announcements, but for the live, we have one more song left, so shouting encore—
を作ってしまったんですけど、あのどうしても歌いたかった曲が1曲ありまして
I went and made it, but there was one song I desperately wanted to sing,
そちらねちょっとあの予約してある枠、このあと10時15分から、あの公開になります。こちら！
and that reserved premiere slot will open right after this at 10:15 PM. Here it is!
オッキミリサイタル！
Okkimi Recital!
こちらをねどうしても歌いたかったんですよ！
I really, really wanted to sing this one!
なので、え頑張る君を何度でも支えてあげたいそんな1曲になっております。
So, it's a song dedicated to supporting you hard workers no matter how many times.
ぜひぜひこっちも聴いてください。これライブ映像となっております。歌ってみたではありません。
Please check it out too! This is a live performance video, not a cover.
今回のライブの延長戦ということで、アンコールとして聴いてください！
As an extension of this live, please enjoy it as an encore!
でですね、あのもう一個なんかあの、ハテナハテナハテナって書いてある、ちょっと謎の枠が当たってたと思うんですけど
And also, there was another mysterious slot with question marks on it, right?
ま、これはねあのちょっと、何？これはいったいあの何物なんだみたいな予約、あのなんか予測してる人とかいたけど、どうすんだこれ全然関係なかったらっていうね。
Some people were guessing what on earth it could be, but what if it has nothing to do with it?
ということで、こちら上がります！怪獣！
With that said, here it is! Kaiju!
こちらお楽しみに待っていてくれたかなと思うので、
I think you've been looking forward to this one,
こちら、え、22時30分から上がります！
so it drops at 22:30!
なのでアンコール聴いてからぜひぜひ怪獣も聴いてくださーい！
So after listening to the encore, please definitely check out Kaiju too!
ということで、あの動画めちゃくちゃすごいです。
Anyway, the video is incredible.
四十雀先生にあのイラスト描いていただいたんですけど、動画もすごいことになっているので、ぜひぜひ見てくださいね！
Shijusara-sensei drew the illustration, and the video turned out amazing, so please check it out!
では、あのちょっと時間もないので、ラスト1曲聴いてください。
Well, we don't have much time left, so please listen to the final song.
あの、オリジナルではないんですけれど、ラスト1曲、いい曲、泣ける曲で、カバーソング1曲聴いてください！
It's not an original, but please listen to this final song—a wonderful, moving cover song!
ではいきますよ！
Here we go!
え、ボーイズビーブレイブ、少年よ勇気を、もっ、持て？勇気を持て！
Um, Boys Be Brave, boys, have cou—have courage! Have courage!
諦められるものは全部
Everything that can be given up
もらうときはひとつだけ
when you receive something is just one.
強情＋笑顔＝愛され上手
Stubbornness + smile = adept at being loved.
長いものにまかれていくほうが楽でも
Even if it's easier to just go with the flow,
Yes, No はっきりさせなくちゃ曖昧ね
you have to make Yes and No clear, or it's vague.
弱気は Bloom Bloom うそが咲く
Timidity blooms, bloom, lies blossom.
お願いするのは全部
Everything you ask for
叶えられるのはひとつ
is just one that can be granted.
純情×感謝＝幸せ上手
Naivety × gratitude = adept at happiness.
石橋だったたきすぎたなら
If you tap the stone bridge too much,
こわれる Yes, No はっきりさせなくちゃ懲りない
it'll break. You won't learn unless you make Yes and No clear.
強気に Wind Wind 華が咲く
Strongly, wind, wind, flowers bloom.
君の選ぶ夢を誰かに頼りにしちゃいけない
You shouldn't rely on someone else for the dream you choose.
けして自分に負けないココロ
A heart that never loses to itself.
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE, hold courage in your hands.
君の選ぶ夢を
The dream you choose
誰かに頼っちゃいけない
you shouldn't depend on anyone for.
だけど決して自分に負けないココロ
Yet a heart that will never lose to itself.
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE, hold courage in your hands.
傷つけることは得意
Being hurtful comes easily,
諦めるのは簡単
and giving up is simple.
後悔−時＝真剣勝負
Regret - time = a serious showdown.
歩いてみなくちゃ犬だって棒にも当たれない
If you don't walk, even a dog won't hit a stick.
Yes, No はっきりさせなくちゃ夕方
You've got to make Yes and No clear by evening,
あの娘は Swing Swing 歌い出す
and that girl starts singing, swing, swing.
強い向かい風に負けずに足をふみだそう
Step forward against the strong headwind without losing.
明日を信じ続けるココロ
A heart that keeps believing in tomorrow.
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE, hold courage in your hands.
君の歩く道でつくろう誇らしい地図を
On the path you walk, let's make a proud map.
世界中でたったひとつの
The one and only in the entire world.
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE, hold courage in your hands.
勇敢を手にして
Grab hold of your courage...
あたえられるものは全部
Everything you're given...
もらうときはひとつだけ
Asking is the only way to get it.
強情＋笑顔＝愛され上手
Stubbornness + Smile = Expert at being loved.
長いものにはまかれていくほうが楽でも
It's easier to just follow the crowd, but...
Yes, No はっきりさせなきゃ
You've gotta make Yes and No clear!
「I, my name…」弱木は Bloom Bloom
"I, my name..." Weakness will Bloom, Bloom.
うそが咲く
Flowers will bloom!
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE! Hold onto your courage!
君の歩く道でつくろう
On the path you walk,
誇らしい地図を
Let's create a proud map.
世界中でたったひとつの
The only one in the whole wide world...
たったひとつの BOYS BE BRAVE
Just one BOYS BE BRAVE!
勇気を手に
Hold onto your courage!
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE! Hold onto your courage!